<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Fragments Solar APP</string>
    <string name="which_planet_is_this">Select the planet that you would like to see its facts!</string>
    <string name="reveal_answer">Reveal Answer</string>
    <string name="next_planet">Next Planet</string>
    <string name="press_here">PRESS HERE TO LEARN ABOUT THE SOLAR SYSTEM</string>
    <string name="select_planet">Select a planet to see its fact !</string>

    <string name="press_here_to_exit">PRESS HERE TO EXIT</string>


    <string-array name="planets_desc">
    <item>
        Mercury
         \n\nINTRODUCTION\n\nMercury has been known to us since 300BC and is a very small planet close to the sun making it hard to see. Mercury can only been seen with a telescope before sunset or just after dawn. It appears as a small spot in front of the surface of the sun. There is no life on Mercury  extreme temperature changes make this impossible.
    </item>
    <item>
        Venus
         \n\nINTRODUCTION\n\nVenus is the second planet from the sun and the hottest one in our solar system with temperatures up to 462 C.It is often referred to as Earths sister planet as they are similar in size mass and density but it is thought to be the least hospitable planet due to its intense heat.Venus is one of the brightest objects in the sky next to the sun and the moon it is the sixth largest planet in our solar system.The surface of the planet is rocky and covered in cratered and volcanic land.It also has clouds on the surface made up of sulphuric acid these clouds are so thick that they stop the heat escaping from the planet keeping the temperature high.
    </item>
    <item>
        Earth
         \n\nINTRODUCTION\n\nEarth is the largest of the inner planets and the only planet in our solar system that is known to support life.Formed around 4.5 billion years ago Earth is the only planet not named after a Roman or Greek God or Goddess instead it is an English/German word meaning the ground.The Earth is the third planet from the sun. Our atmosphere made up of 78 percent nitrogen and 21 percent oxygen protects us from the sun’s ultraviolet solar radiation and incoming meteoroids which mostly break up when entering the atmosphere.ÒEarth orbits the sun every 365 days known as 1 year.
    </item>

    <item>

        Mars
         \n\nINTRODUCTION\n\nMars is the fourth planet from the sun it is also known as the Red Planet due to its red dusty landscape.Named after the Roman god of war Mars is the last one of the inner planets.It has two moons and takes 24 hours and 37 minutes to spin once on its axis. Mars is a rocky planet this is referred to as a terrestrial planet.Over 40 spacecrafts have been launched to explore Mars but only around 16 have been successful.
    </item>

    <item>
        Jupiter
         \n\nINTRODUCTION\n\nJupiter is the largest planet in our solar system with a diameter of 139822 km.Named after the King of gods it is the 5th planet from the sun and the first of the Gas Giants.Jupiter is made up mainly of gas (90 percent hydrogen and 10 percent helium) meaning it does not have a solid surface under its atmosphere there is a liquid ocean of water and hydrogen.Jupiter has four sets of rings the halo ring the main ring the Amalthea gossamer ring and the Thebe gossamer ring these are also referred to as the Jovian ring system.These rings are made up of dust particles. Jupiter is known for its great red spot this spot is a storm that has lasted for over 300 years.Jupiter has a huge magnetic field stronger than any other planet in our solar system. It also has 67 moons over 50 of these are known moons with a further 17 awaiting confirmation of discovery.The four largest moons are Io Europa Ganymede and Callisto and are called the Galilean satellites.
    </item>

   <item>
        Uranus
         \n\nINTRODUCTION\n\nUranus named after the Greek god of the sky is the seventh planet from the sun and the third largest in our solar system.Known mainly as one of the Gas Giants due to its atmosphere of mainly hydrogen helium and methane Uranus is also called an Ice Giant as 80 percent or more if the planet is made up of icy materials.Unlike the other planets Uranus spins on its side at an angle of 98 percent scientists believe this is due to a object the size of earth crashing into it causing it to rotate horizontally.
    </item>

    <item>
        Saturn
         \n\nINTRODUCTION\n\nSaturn is the sixth planet from the sun and is the second largest after Jupiter.Also known as one of the Gas Giants Saturn does not have a solid surface.Its atmosphere is made up of predominantly hydrogen and helium.  This planet was named after the Roman God of agriculture.Like all the Gas Giants Saturn also has rings surrounding it they are a mixture of Ice rock and dust particles however its rings are the largest of the four Gas Giants and the brightest.It also has about 53 known moons and moonlets with at least 9 more waiting confirmation of discovery. One of these moons is Titan and is the only moon in our solar system to have its own atmosphere.
    </item>

    <item>
        Neptune
         \n\nINTRODUCTION\n\nNeptune is the most distant planet in our solar system located 4.5 billion Km from the Sun.Named after the God of the Sea, Neptune is the fourth largest Planet and like the other Gas Giants is made up mostly of hydrogen, helium and methane.Neptune was not known about for many centuries due to its distance, it was finally discovered in 1846. Neptune has thirteen confirmed moons with one more awaiting confirmation of discovery.
    </item>

    </string-array>

    <integer-array name="planet_images">
        <item>@drawable/mercury</item>
        <item>@drawable/venus</item>
        <item>@drawable/earth</item>
        <item>@drawable/mars</item>
        <item>@drawable/jupiter</item>
        <item>@drawable/uranus</item>
        <item>@drawable/saturn</item>
        <item>@drawable/neptune</item>
    </integer-array>

    <string-array name="planet_names">
        <item>Mercury</item>
        <item>Venus</item>
        <item>Earth</item>
        <item>Mars</item>
        <item>Jupiter</item>
        <item>Uranus</item>
        <item>Saturn</item>
        <item>Neptune</item>


    </string-array>
    <string name="title_activity_planet_facts_fragment">PlanetFactsFragment</string>
</resources>
